Guide to the Adler hip hop archive, circa 1970-2013.
Adler hip hop archive
- Series II. Posters and Framed Items
  - Now That's What I Call Music 3, 1999; 31
    Notes: Awarded to Lyor Cohen to Commemorate the sale of more than 1,000,000 copies of the album "Now 2"
  - Now That's What I Call Music 3, 1999; 32
    Notes: Awarded to Lyor Cohen to Commemorate the sale of more than 2,000,000 copies of the album "Now 3"
  - Shania Twain, 1999; 33
    Notes: Awarded to Lyor Cohen to Commemorate the sale of 250, 000 copies of the Mercury Records album "Come on Over" (in German)
  - Violator, 1999; 34
    Notes: Advertisement for Montage moving billboards
  - Bon Jovi, May 2000; 35
    Event / Title: Gold and Platinum Awards
    Notes: Awarded to Lyor Cohen for the sale of 300,000 copies of "Crush" in Germany (in German.)
  - O Brother Where Art Thou, c. 2000; 36
    Notes: Awarded to Lyor Cohen for the sale of 1,000,000 copies of the soundtrack record
  - Now That's What I Call Music 4, 2000; 37
    Notes: Awarded to Lyor Cohen to Commemorate the sale of more than 2,000,000 copies of the album "Now 4"
  - Now That's What I Call Music 5, c. 2000; 38
    Notes: Awarded to Lyor Cohen to Commemorate the sale of more than 4,000,000 copies of the album "Now 5"
  - Ryan Adams, 2001; 39
    Notes: Awarded to Lyor Cohen to recognize sales in the United Kingdom of 100,000 copies of the Lost Highways album "Gold"
  - Now That's What I Call Music 8, c. 2001; 40
    Notes: Awarded to Lyor Cohen to Commemorate the sale of more than 4,000,000 copies of the album "Now 8"
  - Christina Milian, March 2002; 41
    Event / Title: Gold Disc
    Notes: Presented to Lyor Cohen to Commemorate the sales of 100,000 copies. Def Jam Japan
  - Now That's What I Call Music 10, c. 2002; 42
    Notes: Awarded to Lyor Cohen to Commemorate the sale of more than 2,000,000 copies of the album "Now 10"
  - Lucinda Williams, July 9, 2001; 43
    Event / Title: Time Magazine
    Notes: Framed cover of Time Magazine issue featuring Lucinda Williams as America's Best Songwriter
  - Bill Adler, undated; 44
    Notes: Awarded to Bill Adler "Ill Badler" to commemorate 6 platinum years at Rush Artist Management
  - Hits Daily Double, undated; 45
    Event / Title: Award to Lyor Cohen - Island Def Jam
  - Lyor Cohen, undated; 46
    Event / Title: Award
    Notes: Awards to Lyor Cohen "In recognition of your efforts which resulted in the successful launch of the Island Def Jam Music Group"
- Series III. Records and Other Media
  Records are arranged alphabetically in the collection. All albums have been individually cataloged (to find an album of a particular artist please search our on-line catalog.)
  - Records
    - Aleem - Kurtis Blow, SR-5566-5605 (Box 30)
    - Kurtis Blow - Common, SR-5606-5650 (Box 31)
    - The Conscious Daughters - DST, SR-5651-5699 (Box 32)
    - Dynasty and Mimi - Force M.D.'s, SR-5700-5745 (Box 33)
    - Doug E. Fresh - Ice-T, SR-5746-5786 (Box 34)
    - Inspectah Deck - Big Daddy Kane, SR-5787-5832 (Box 35)
    - Kelis - Mobb Deep, SR-5833-5878 (Box 36)
    - Monie Love - D.J. Red Alert, SR-5879-5929 (Box 37)
    - Red Man - Run-DMC, SR-5930-5977 (Box 38)
    - Salt-N-Pepa - Spoonie Gee, SR-5978-6022 (Box 39)
    - Spyder D, featuring D.J. Doc - A Tribe Called Quest, SR-6023-6069 (Box 40)
    - Two Live Crew - Young Black Teenagers, SR-6070-6115 (Box 41)
    - Compilations, SR-6116-6161 (Box 42)
    - 7 inch records, SR-6162-6218 (Box 43)
  - DVDs
    - 80 Blocks from Tiffany's, 2010; DVD-1079 (Box 44)
    - American Revolutionaries: DMC, 2011; DVD-1080 (Box 44)
    - And You Don't Stop: 30 Years of Hip Hop, Episodes 1-5, c. 2004; DVD-1081-1083 (Box 44)
    - Beat Kings: The story of Hip Hop, 2006; DVD-1084 (Box 44)
    - Big Fun in the Big Town, 2012 (1986); DVD-1085 (Box 44)
    - Biggie and Tupac: The Story Behind the Murder of Rap's Biggest Superstars, 2002; DVD-1086 (Box 44)
    - Big Pun: The Legacy, 2009; DVD-1087 (Box 44)
    - Big Pun: Still Not a Player, 2002; DVD-1088 (Box 44)
    - The Biz, Season 1, Episodes 1 and 2, 2005; DVD-1089-1090 (Box 44)
    - Bomb It!: The Global Graffiti Documentary, 2007; DVD-1091 (Box 44)
    - Brave New Voices: Episode 102 and 103, 2009; DVD-1092-1093 (Box 44)
    - Celebrity Crime Files: Jam Master Jay (2 copies), November 2009; DVD-1094-1095 (Box 44)
    - Dead Prez: It's Bigger than Hip-Hop, c. 1999; DVD-1096 (Box 44)
    - DMC: My Adoption Journey, March 27, 2006; DVD-1097 (Box 44)
    - Downtown Calling, 2009; DVD-1098 (Box 44)
    - Driven: LL Cool J, July 2006; DVD-1099 (Box 44)
    - Get Jay-Z for Me, DVD-1100-1101 (Box 44)
    - The Guy Fisher Story, 2008; DVD-1102 (Box 44)
    - Hip Hop 101: The Game, 2003; DVD-1103, CD-2147 (Box 44)
    - Hip Hop by da bay, 2005; DVD-1104 (Box 44)
    - Hip Hop Immortals, 2004; DVD-1105 (Box 44)
    - Hip Hop Honors, 2007; DVD-1106 (Box 44)
    - Hip Hop Honors: Def Jam, 2009; DVD-1107 (Box 44)
    - Hip Hop Slam TV '93, Vol 3,6-8, 1993; DVD-1108-1111 (Box 44)
    - Hollywood Heat: The Murder of Jam Master Jay, March 13, 2008; DVD-1112 (Box 44)
    - Hollywood Heat, segment about Irv Gotti - Murder Inc., November 29, 2007; DVD-1113 (Box 44)
    - Just for Kicks, 2006; DVD-1114 (Box 44)
    - The Larry Davis Story, c. 2008; DVD-1115 (Box 44)
    - The Last Poets, 2009; DVD-1116 (Box 44)
    - Life After - TV One, June 2012; DVD-1117 (Box 44)
    - Nothing But The Beat, 2011; DVD-1118 (Box 44)
    - The Original 50 Cent, 2005; DVD-1119 (Box 44)
    - Rappin' with the Rickster, No Date; DVD-1120 (Box 44)
    - Rappin' with the Rickster - 2 DVD Set, 2010; DVD-1121-1122 (Box 44)
    - The Raw Report: Yung Ralph, The Jung Man, No Date; DVD-1155 (Box 44)
    - The Raw Report: Shawty Lo, The Real Bankhead Story, No Date; DVD-1156 (Box 44)
    - The Raw Report: BMF Entertainment, No Date; DVD-1157 (Box 44)
    - Run-DMC - Biography, May 2008; DVD-1158 (Box 44)
    - Scratch - 2 DVD Set, 2002; DVD-1159-1160 (Box 44)
    - Sneaker Stories, c.2009, 2011; DVD-1161 (Box 44)
    - Two Turntables and a Microphone, 2008; DVD-1162 (Box 44)
      Jam Master Jay Documentary
    - Videos That Rocked the World, Beastie Boys: "Fight for Your Right", December 7, 2007; DVD-1163 (Box 44)
    - Videos That Rocked the World, Public Enemy: "Fight the Power", December 5, 2007; DVD-1164 (Box 44)
    - Videos That Rocked the World, Run-DMC: "Walk This Way", November 28, 2007; DVD-1165 (Box 44)
    - Who? Mag TV, c.2010; DVD-1166 (Box 44)
    - Wigger Please, 2006; DVD-1167 (Box 44)
    - World News America: Kool Lady Blue, November 17, 2008; DVD-1168 (Box 44)
    - WS50: The Video Album, 2004; DVD-1169 (Box 44)
SEPARATED MATERIAL
Books - cataloged individually in the Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections
Legend 01: Walt "Clyde" Frazier; [foreword by Clyde]. - [United States?]: Puma c2005. - Rare Books GV749.S64 L44 - Inscribed by Walt Frazier to Bill Adler.
Beaty, rymy, z?ycie: leksykon muzyki hip-hop / Radek Miszczak ... [et al.]. - Poznan´: Wydawn. Kurpisz S.A., c2005. - Rare Books ML102.R27 B43 2005 - Inscribed to Bill Adler by the editors.
Droppin' science: straight-up talk from hip hop's greatest voices / selected and edited by Denise L. McIver. - New York: Three Rivers Press, c2002. - Rare Books PN6084.C556 D76 2002
Free style: [interviews / Desse & SBG]. - Paris: F. Massot & F. Millet, c1993. - Rare Books ML3531 .F74 1993
Sneaker freaker. - Melbourne: Sneaker Freaker. - Rare Books GV749.S64 S64 Volumes: issue 16-18
Tupac Amaru Shakur, 1971-1996 / by the editors of Vibe; editor Alan Light. - New York: Crown, c1997. - Rare Books ML420.S529 T87 1997+
Wax poetics anthology. - Brooklyn, N.Y.: Wax Poetics Books, c2007- - Rare Books ML3470 .W39 2008+ Volumes: v.1 - Inscribed to Bill Adler from Andre´.
VX: 10 years of VIBE photography / [collected] by Rob Kenner & George Pitts; with a foreword by Quincy Jones. - [United States]: VIBE Books in association with Harry N. Abrams, 2003. - Rare Books ML3531 .V8 2003 ++
Superstar 35 / [edited by Thomas Marecki; preface by Ulf Poschardt]. - [Europe]: Marok in association with Adidas, c2005. - Rare Books GV749.S64 S87+
Move the crowd: voices and faces of the hip-hop nation / [compiled by] Gregor and Dimitri Ehrlich; photographs by Jesse Frohman. - New York: MTV Books/Pocket Books, 1999. - Rare Books ML3531 .M68 1999+
Def Jam Recordings: la saga du label rap mythique / [textes, Bill Adler, Dan Charnas; prefaces, Rick Rubin, Russel Simmons, Lyor Cohen, Kevin liles, Olivier Cachin; introduction, Kelefa Sanneh]. - [Paris]: Verlhac Editions, 2011. - Rare Books ML3792.D44 D44 2011b ++
Run DMC: world tour. - [San Francisco: Rush Productions, c1986] - Rare Books ML421.R93 R93 1986+
Whodini in concert. - [San Francisco: Rush Productions, 1987] - Rare Books ML421.W624 W56 1987+
Frank 151. - Atlanta, GA: Stephen Malbon, 1999- - Rare Books TR659.8 .F73 tiny Volumes: book 18 book 24 chapter 43 chapter 49
Beastie boys: Licensed to ill tour 1987: picture book. - [San Francisco: Winterland Productions, 1987?] - Rare Books ML421.B365 B3656 1978 ++
Run DMC: tougher than leather. - [San Francisco, 1987] - Rare Books ML421.R93 R93 1987 ++ - Inscribed to Bill Adler on the cover.
Eric B. & Rakim: tour book 1988. - [United States, 1988?] - Rare Books ML421.E75 E75 1988 ++ - Inscribed to Bill Adler by Eric B. and Rakim.
Hip-hop story: Sidney / [Sophie Bramly, Olivier Carrie, Laurence Touitou]. - Paris: Hachette Jeunesse, 1984. - Rare Books ML3531 .B736+ - Inscribed by Sophie Bramly to Bill Adler.
Def Jam Recordings: the first 25 years of the last great record label / [essays by Bill Adler and Dan Charnas; prefaces by Rick Rubin, Russel Simmons, Lyor Cohen and Kevin Liles; introduction by Kelefa Sanneh]. - New York: Rizzoli; Enfield: Publishers Group UK [distributor], 2011, c2010. - Rare Books ML3792.D44 D44 2011 ++
Nation conscious rap / [edited by Joseph D. Eure & James G. Spady]. - New York: PC International Press, c1991. - Rare Books ML3531 .N27 - Softcover. Inscribed to Bill Adler by James G. Spady.
Bronx biannual. - New York, N.Y.: Akashic Books, c2006- - Rare Books PS153.N5 B76 Volumes: no.1 (2006)
Beats, rhymes & life: what we love and hate about hip-hop / edited by Kenji Jasper and Ytasha Womack; photos by Robert Johnson III; reporting-at-large by Mark Allwood. [Foreword by Michael Eric Dyson.] - New York: Harlem Moon/Broadway Books, c2007. Electronic Access: http://www.loc.gov/catdir/toc/ecip0619/2006025892.html - Rare Books E185.86 .B3775 2007
Hip-Hop divas. - New York: Three Rivers Press, c2001. - Rare Books ML3531 .H57 2001+
Bum rush the page: a Def Poetry Jam / edited by Tony Medina and Louis Reyes Rivera. - New York: Three Rivers Press, c2001. - Rare Books PS615 .B86 2001
Stop the violence: overcoming self destruction / edited by Nelson George for the National Urban League. - New York: Pantheon Books, c1990. - Rare Books ML3531 .S88+
50 Cent (Musician) - From pieces to weight: once upon a time in Southside Queens / 50 Cent. - New York: Pocket Books/MTV Books, 2006. - Rare Books ML420.F54 A3 2006
Adams, Cey. - Definition: the art and design of hip-hop / Cey Adams with Bill Adler; foreword by Russell Simmons. - New York: Collins Design, c2008. - Rare Books HN59.2 .A33 2008
Adler, Bill, 1951- - Graffiti / compiled by Bill Adler. - New York: Pyramid Books, c1967. - Rare Books GT3913.A2 A35 1967
Adler, Bill, 1951- - Tougher than leather: the authorized biography of Run-DMC / B. Adler. - New York: New American Library, c1987. - Rare Books ML421.R93 A66 1987
Adler, Bill, 1951- - L.L. Cool J in concert. - [San Francisco: Rush Productions, 1987] - Rare Books ML420.L14 L14 1987+
Adler, Bill, 1951- - Tougher than leather / Bill Adler. - Los Angeles, Calif.: Consafos Press, 2002. - Rare Books ML421.R93 A66 2002
Alexander, Frank. - Got your back: the life of a bodyguard in the hardcore world of gangsta rap / Frank Alexander with Heidi Siegmund Cuda. - New York: St. Martin's Press, 1998. - Rare Books ML420.S529 A8 1998
Batey, Angus. - Rhyming & stealing: a history of the Beastie Boys / by Angus Batey. - London: Independent Music Press, 1998. - Rare Books ML421.B365 B35 1998
Baughan, Brian. - LL Cool J / Brian Baughan. - Broomall, Pa.: Mason Crest Publishers, c2008. - Rare Books ML420.L14 B38 2008
Beckman, Janette. - The breaks: stylin' and profilin' 1982-1990 / Janette Beckman; texts by Tom Terrell, Bill Adler. - Brooklyn, NY: PowerHouse Books, 2007. - Rare Books ML87 .B359 2007 - Inscribed by Janet Beckman to Bill Adler.
Beckman, Janette. - Rap!: portraits and lyrics of a generation of Black rockers / photographs by Janette Beckman; text by B. Adler; foreword by Doctor Dre and Ed Lover. - New York: St. Martin's Press, 1991. - Rare Books ML3531 .B39+
Benabib, Michael. - In ya grill: the faces of hip-hop / photography by Michael Benabib; text by Bill Adler. - New York, NY: Billboard Books, c2007. - Rare Books ML3531 .B45 2007
Berne, Emma Carlson. - Snoop Dogg / Emma Carlson-Berne. - Broomall, Pa.: Mason Crest Publishers, c2007. - Rare Books ML420.S665 B47 2007
Boyd, Todd. - The new H.N.I.C. (head niggas in charge): the death of civil rights and the reign of hip hop / Todd Boyd. - New York: New York University Press, c2002. - Rare Books E185.86 .B649 2002
Brackman, Harold David. - Jew on the brain: a public refutation of the Nation of Islam's The Secret relationship between Blacks and Jews / by Harold Brackman; foreword by Bill Adler; afterword by Cornel West. - [Los Angeles? CA]: H. Brackman, c1992. - Rare Books E184.36.A34 B73
Brown, Ethan, 1972- - Queens reigns supreme: Fat Cat, 50 Cent and the rise of the hip-hop hustler / Ethan Brown. - New York: Anchor Books, 2005. - Rare Books HV6452.N7 B76 2005
Brown, Terrell, 1957- - Reverend Run (Run-D.M.C.) / Terrell Brown. - Broomall, Pa.: Mason Crest Publishers, c2007. - Rare Books BR1725.S4675 B76 2007
Bua, Justin. - The beat of urban art: the art of Justin Bua. - New York: HC, c2007. - Rare Books N6537.B825 A4 2007 - Inscribed by Justin Bua to Bill Adler.
Cable, Andrew. - A family affair: the unauthorized Sean "Puffy" Combs Story / Andrew Cable. - New York: Ballantine Books, c1998. - Rare Books ML420.D549 C33 1998
Campbell, Luther, 1960- - As nasty as they wanna be: the uncensored story of Luther Campbell of the 2 Life Crew / Luther Campbell & John R. Miller. - Kingston, Jamaica: Kingston Publishers, c1992. - Rare Books ML420.C223 A3 1992
Campbell, Shanetris, 1982- - I am not my father's daughter: a memoir of my life as Luther Campbell's daughter / Shanetris Campbell. - Miami, Fla.: Publicly Owned Publishing Co., c2011. - Rare Books E185.86 .C29
Chang, Jeff. - Can't stop, won't stop: a history of the hip-hop generation / Jeff Chang; introduction by DJ Kool Herc. - New York: Picador, 2006. - Rare Books ML3531 .C5 2006
Chang, Jeff. - Can't stop, won't stop: a history of the hip-hop generation / Jeff Chang; introduction by DJ Kool Herc. - New York: St. Martin's Press, 2005. - Rare Books ML3531 .C5 2005 - With dust jacket. Inscribed by the author: "To Afrika Bambaataa, without you, this wouldn't be. For all your courage, vision, love and inspiration, thank you, with love and respect, Jeff Chang." Sent to Bam on Jan. 29, 2005 in a St. Martin's Press padded envelope with delivery confirmation requested. ____________ - Rare Books ML3531 .C5 2005 - With dust jacket. Inscribed by the author to Bill Adler.
Chuck D, 1960- - Fight the power: rap, race, and reality / Chuck D. with Yusuf Jah. [Foreword by Spike Lee] - New York, N.Y.: Delacorte Press, c1997. - Rare Books ML3531 .D2 1997
Cohn, Nik. - Triksta: life and death and New Orleans rap / Nik Cohn. - New York: Vintage Books, 2007. - Rare Books ML3531 .C64 2007
Coleman, Brian, 1970- - Check the technique: liner notes for hip-hop junkies / Brian Coleman. [Introduction by Ahrmir "?uestlove" Thompson.] - New York: Villard, 2007. - Rare Books ML3531 .C65 2007 - Inscribed by the author to Bill Adler.
Coleman, Brian, 1970- - Rakim told me: hip-hop wax facts, straight from the original artists: the '80s / [Brian Coleman]. - Somerville, MA: Wax Facts, c2005. - Rare Books ML394 .C65 2005
Cooper, Martha. - Subway art / Martha Cooper and Henry Chalfant. - New York: Henry Holt and Co., [1996, c1984. - Rare Books GT3913.N72 C77 1996+
Costello, Mark. - Signifying rappers: rap and race in the urban present / Mark Costello and David Foster Wallace. - New York: Ecco Press: Distributed by W.W. Norton, 1990. - Rare Books ML3531 .C84
Cotts, Nat. - Young Jeezy / Nat Cotts. - Broomall, Pa.: Mason Crest Publishers, c2008. - Rare Books ML3930.Y68 C68 2008
Cross, Brian. - It's not about a salary--: rap, race, and resistance in Los Angeles / Brian Cross. - London; New York: Verso, 1993 [i.e. 1994] - Rare Books ML3531 .C95 1993
Cunningham, Doug. - The early bird: the art and design of Morning Breath / [by Doug Cunningham and Jason Noto]. - San Francisco, Calif.: Upper Playground: Fifty 24SF Gallery, 2006. - Rare Books NC999.4.M67 M67 2006
DMC (Musician) - King of rock: respect, responsibility, and my life with Run-DMC / Darryl McDaniels with Bruce Haring; foreword by Will Smith. - New York: St. Martin's Press, 2001. - Rare Books ML420.D62 A3 2001 - Inscribed to Bill Adler by the author. With dust jacket.
Dufresne, David. - Yo! re´volution rap: l'histoire, les groupes, le mouvement / David Dufresne. - [Paris]: Ramsay, c1991. - Rare Books ML3531 .D86 - Inscribed to Bill Adler by the author.
Dyson, Michael Eric. - Between God and gangsta rap: bearing witness to black culture / Michael Eric Dyson. - New York: Oxford University Press, 1997. - Rare Books E185.86 .D94 1997
Dyson, Michael Eric. - Holler if you hear me: searching for Tupac Shakur / Michael Eric Dyson. - New York: Basic Civitas Books, c2001. - Rare Books ML420.S517 D99 2001
Eminem, 1972- - Angry blonde / Eminem. - New York: Regan Books, c2000. - Rare Books ML420.E53 A3 2000
Fab 5 Freddy, 1959- - Fresh fly flavor: words & phrases of the hip-hop generation / Fab 5 Freddy. - Stamford, CT: Longmeadow Press, c1992. - Rare Books PE3727.N4 F12 1992
Fedorchak, Vincent. - Fuzz one: a Bronx childhood / by Vincent Fedorchak. - New York, N. Y.: Testify Books: [distributed by] D.A.P., 2005. - Rare Books ND2639.F44 A2 2005
Fernando, S. H. - The new beats: exploring the music, culture, and attitudes of hip-hop / S.H. Fernando. - New York: Anchor Books/Doubleday, c1994. - Rare Books ML3531 .F36 - Inscribed by the author to Bill Adler.
Flavor Flav, 1959- - Flavor Flav: the icon, the memoir. - Las Vegas, NV: Farrah Gray Pub., c2011. - Rare Books ML420.F56 A3 2011
Franti, Michael, 1968- - Food for the masses: lyrics & portraits / photography by Wonder Knack. - San Rafael, CA: Insight Editions, c2006. - Rare Books ML54.6.F73 S62 2006+ - With DVD of concert footage in pocket inside back cover.
Fresh, Freddy, 1963- - Freddy Fresh presents the rap records. - Rare Books ML156.4.R27 F74 2008 - Author's signed presentation copy to Bill Adler.
Fricke, Jim. - Yes yes y'all: the Experience Music Project oral history of hip-hop's first decade / Jim Fricke, Charlie Ahearn. - Cambridge, MA: Da Capo Press, c2002. - Rare Books ML3531 .F75 2002 - Softcover.
Friedman, Glen E. - Fuck you too: extras + more scrapbook / Glen E. Friedman. - Los Angeles, CA: 2. 13. 61 Publications Inc. in association with Burning Flags Press, 1996. - Rare Books ML87 .F835
Friedman, Glen E. - Fuck you too: extras + more scrapbook / Glen E. Friedman. - Los Angeles, CA: ConSafos; [New York]: Burning Flags Press, 1996. - Rare Books ML87 .F835 1996 - 2nd printing. In black paper wrappers, with excerpt from Super-X, Tokyo, '96, on inside front flap.
Friedman, Glen E. - Fuck you heroes: Glen E. Friedman photographs, 1976-1991, with annotated index / introduction by C.R. Stecyk, III. - New York: Burning Flags Press, 1994. - Rare Books ML87 .F85 1994+
Garcia, Bobbito. - Where'd you get those?: New York City's sneaker culture, 1960-1987 / Bobbito Garcia. - New York, N.Y.: Testify Books, c2003. - Rare Books GV749.S64 G37 2003
Golus, Carrie, 1969- - Russell Simmons / Carrie Golus. - Minneapolis: Twenty-First Century Books, c2008. - Rare Books ML429.S56 G65 2008
Greenberg, Keith Elliot, 1959- - Rap / Keith Elliot Greenberg. - Minneapolis: Lerner Publications Co., c1988. - Rare Books ML3477 .G74 1988
Gueraseva, Stacy. - Def Jam, Inc.: Russell Simmons, Rick Rubin, and the extraordinary story of the world's most influential hip hop label / Stacy Gueraseva. - New York: One World Ballantine, c2005. - Rare Books ML427.D44 G84 2005 - Inscribed by the author to Bill Adler.
Hamilton, Toby G. - DMX / Toby G. Hamilton. - Broomall, Pa.: Mason Crest Publishers, c2008. - Rare Books ML420.D105 H36 2008
Hamilton, Toby G. - Busta Rhymes / Toby G. Hamilton. - Broomall, Pa.: Mason Crest, c2008. - Rare Books ML420.B93 H36 2008
Haring, Keith. - Art in transit: subway drawings / by Keith Haring; photos by Tseng Kwong Chi; introduction by Henry Geldzahler; design by Dan Friedman. - New York: Harmony Books, c1984. - Rare Books NC139.H3 A4 1984+
Heller, Jerry, 1940- - Gangsta rap attitude: les impitoyables memoires d'un juif blanc devenu le plus grand manager du rap noir en Californie / Jerry Heller [with] Gil Reavill; traduction et preface Olivier Cachin; illustrations de Gabriel Gay. - Paris: Scali, c2007. - Rare Books ML429.H383 A3 2007 - Translation of: Ruthless: a memoir. Provenance: translator's signed presentation copy to Bill Adler.
Hewitt, Paolo, 1958- - "Rap beats to the rhyme" / compiled by Paolo Hewitt & Tim Westwood. - London; New York: Omnibus, 1989. - Rare Books ML3531 .R216 1989 ++
Huxley, Martin. - Eminem: crossing the line / Martin Huxley. - New York: St. Martin's Griffin, 2000. - Rare Books ML420.E53 H98 2000
Ice-T (Musician) - Ice: a memoir of gangster life and redemption-- from South Central to Hollywood / Ice-T and Douglas Century. - New York: One World/Ballantine Books, c2011. - Rare Books ML420.I3 A3
Ice-T (Musician) - The Ice opinion: who gives a fuck? / Ice-T as told to Heidi Siegmund. - New York: St. Martin's Press, 1994. - Rare Books ML420.I3 A5
Ito¯, Yasuko, author. - NY hippu hoppu dori¯mu / Ito¯ Yasuko = Urban chronicle by Yasuko Ito. - To¯kyo¯: Shinko¯ Myu¯jikku, 2004. - Rare Books ML3531 .I76 2004 - Author's signed presentation copy to Bill Adler. With dust jacket and publisher's wrapper.
J-Zone, 1977- - Root for the villain: rap, bullshit, and a celebration of failure / J-Zone. - Cambria Heights, NY: Old Maid Entertainment, 2011. - Rare Books ML420.J115 A3 2011
James, Todd. - Todd James. - [New York, NY]: Testify Books; Distributed by PowerHouse Books, c2002, 2003 - Rare Books N7433.4 .J35 T6 2003
Jenkins, Sacha. - Piecebook: the secret drawings of graffiti writers / Sacha Jenkins, David Villorente. - Munich; New York, N.Y.: Prestel, c2008. - Rare Books ND2590 .J46 2008+
Kitwana, Bakari. - The hip hop generation: young Blacks and the crisis in African American culture / Bakari Kitwana. - New York: Basic Civitas, c2002. - Rare Books E185.86 .K58 2002
Knuckles, Jeffrey D. - The rap! book: a book / by Jeffrey D. Knuckles. - Los Angeles, CA: Holloway House Pub. Co., c1988. - Rare Books PS3561.N725 R37 1988
KRS-One (Musician), author. - The science of rap / by KRS-One. - [Englewood, N. J., c1996] - Rare Books ML3531 .K78 1996
Krulik, Nancy E. - M.C. Hammer & Vanilla Ice: the hip-hop never stops! / by Nancy E. Krulik. - New York, N.Y.: Scholastic, c1991. - Rare Books ML400 .K78
Kwon, Sue. - Street level: New York photographs, 1987-2007 / Sue Kwon. [Introduction by Hilton Als]. - New York: Testify Books: Available through D.A.P./Distributed Art Publishers, c2009. - Rare Books TR659.8 .K86 2009+ - Inscribed by the author to Bill Adler.
Lapassade, Georges. - Le rap, ou, la fureur de dire: essai / George Lapassade, Philippe Rousselot. - Paris: L. Talmart, c1990. - Rare Books ML3531 .L29
Lawlor, Michelle. - Missy Elliott / Michelle Lawlor. - Broomall, Pa.: Mason Crest Publishers, c2007. - Rare Books ML420.E45 L39 2007